Shwetha J

Frontend Developer

Proficient front end developer with 2.10 years of experience in designing and building responsive websites for the insurance domain. Boosted production efficiency by 40% with product quality satisfaction over 99%. Looking forward to create more seamless UI experience.

shwethaj1104@gmail.com

+91 8197322687

portfolio-shwetha.vercel.app/

linkedin.com/in/shwetha-j-b26883159

github.com/shwethaj1104

0

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer I

Think N Solutions

Bengaluru

11/2020 - Present Achievements/Tasks

- Strengthened web performance including loading, interactivity and accessibility by 80%.
- Increased user satisfaction by 35% while successfully meeting deadlines.
- Led team of 2 interns to develop a web based ecommerce application using angular.
- Revamped UI of an e-commerce website that enhanced its performance and improved load time by 35%.
- Best Performer Think N Solutions | Dec 2021.

Intern

Think N Solutions

01/2020 - 11/2020

Bengaluru

Achievements/Tasks

- Optimized UI for various screens using flexbox, grid and media queries reducing 20% of code.
- Documented the product for ease of understanding, hence cutting the time spent by team up to 50%.
- Ensured image optimization is automated and achieved less than 3 second load time.

Internship DRDO

06/2019 - 12/2019

Bengaluru

Achievements/Tasks

- As part of MTech project, worked with senior scientists at DRDO for 6 months.
- Close observation on Radar design.
- Developed a 90% efficient radar target simulator for passive radar.

EDUCATION

Master of technology (MTech)

Dayananda Sagar college of engineering

07/2018 - 06/2020

Bengaluru

SGPA: 9.7

 Earned opportunity to work on a project under Head of department.

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.) Vemana Institute of technology

06/2018 - 05/2018

Bengaluru

Percentage: 85%

 Recognized top rank holder by VTU

SKILLS



PROJECTS

Contract Claim Application - United States (React) (01/2022 - Present)

- Payment details generation application for claiming insurance.
- Involved 100% from scratch of project to Production of UI.

Managing Rules for the contracts – United states (Angular) (07/2021 - 12/2021)

- A user friendly UI application to apply rules for cancellation of vehicle insurance.
- Reduced paper work till 50%.
- Added crucial features of multi language support with 100% on time delivery of product.

Contract Cancellation – United states (Angular) (02/2021 - 07/2021)

- Developed a well organized vehicle insurance contract cancellation application.
- Appreciation for well accessible UI design.

E-commerce Website - (React) (11/2020 - 02/2021)

- Designed 2 attractive websites with 99% client satisfaction.
- Turned in projects an average of 10% more responsive.

File management system - (Angular) (07/2020 - 10/2020)

- Responsible handling a high volume of inbound customer requests per day.
- 30% increase in user experience.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Led team of 3 to deliver new customer support system.

UI designs for 7+ software applications for tablets and mobile devices with various screen sizes.

Guided 2 interns in creating sample designs for the company website.

Increased code-efficiency for applications by 40%.

INTERESTS

Routine learner Travel Explore advance solutions

Adding up new skills Learning languages Art